Thanks to the hard work of interns and contributors
GNOME announce the version 3.18
In this release GNOME improves the general user experience for users and new developers alike
If you computer has a light sensor
GNOME can now use it automatically adjust the brightness of your screen
the touchscreen experience has also improved when selecting and modifying text
"Files" has received a lot of attention this cycle
there's a new view in the sidebar
so remote and internal locations are collected in one place for your convenience
Progress is now shown in the header bar when files are being copy
There are many other improvements
inlcuding  a more polished search function,
Google Drive integration
and better file management.
"Software" has become the first suport updating device firmware
use new Linux Vendor firmware service
The service allows vendors to submit firmware
and GNOME Software allow allow you to install it with the click of a button
Further more, the GNOME community has improved a large variety of Apps.
including "Calendar"
which now comes with a management dialog to help you manage your calendars.
Polari
with a better initially user experience.
GNOME Documents
which is supporting a revamped user interface for organizing your documents.
And Evince
which annotation and video support has improved.
GNOME 3.18 comes with a preview of the GNOME To Do
a personal task manager helping you keep track of the tasks ahead of time.
GNOME development tools have also improved in this cycles
Builder for example
now has a source code minimap
a shortcut overview
and an auto completion for Python
the Human Interface Guidelines have been restructured
and including new usage pattern.
GNOME Logs user interface now goes better overview
I can show you logs from the last five boots.
Boxes has improved interface
with the new list view
for users with a lot of virtual machines.
Finally GTK+ has received new typographic features
A new GNOME relase is available for you
as a live image to try now.
Many distributions will also ship  GNOME 3.18 in the near future.
GNOME is a friendly community making free software for everyone.
Excited?
join us in making the perfect desktop environment!